A Guide to the John D. Rockefeller 3rd papers, Associates, Porter McKeever FA1214
Rockefeller Archive Center
John D. Rockefeller 3rd papers, Associates, Porter McKeever
1972-1980
Rockefeller Archive Center
McKeever, Porter
Rockefeller, John D., III (John Davison), 1906-1978
FA1214
2.62 Cubic Feet 2 standard record storage boxes.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC.
Arrangement
As received.
Biographical / Historical
Porter McKeever, joined John D. Rockefeller 3rd's staff in 1973 as a senior advisor after a long career in public administration and international relations.
McKeever had served as Director of Information of the U.S. Mission to the United Nations from 1946 to 1952.
In 1953, he was appointed Director of Public Information at the Ford Foundation and served a similar role with the Council for Economic Development.
In 1964, McKeever founded and became the first president of the United Nations Association of the United States.
In the late 1980s, McKeever authored a biography of Adlai Stevenson II.
Scope and Contents
The collections contains correspondence, memoranda, chronological files and a variety of meeting records, as well as documentation of the long-standing professional contacts and relationships fostered by Porter McKeever and John D. Rockefeller 3rd.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The McKeever collection was donated to RAC by the JDR 3rd estate as a part of the John D. Rockefeller 3rd papers.
- Correspondence - A-C, 1973-1980 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Asia Trip, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Bicentennial, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Business Committee for the Arts, 1978-1980 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Dempsey, 1978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Joan Dunlop, 1975-1977 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Correspondence - D-F, 1974-1979 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Ethics in Acquisition, 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Filer Commission, 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 9-10)
- Correspondence - G-J, 1974-1979 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Japan Society, 1978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 12-13)
- Peter Johnson, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Correspondence - K-M, 1972-1979 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- League of Women Voters, 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Members of Congress for Peace through Law (MCPL) (Box 1, Folder 17)
- McLean, Donald, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Myers Chair, Cornell, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Correspondence - N, 1977-1979 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- New Directions, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- O'Connell, Bryan, 1979-1980 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Overseas Education Fund, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Population, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Correspondence - O-P, 1974-1979 (Box 1, Folder 24A)
- Press Foundation of Asia, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Correspondence - R, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Correspondence - S, 1974-1979 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Selyer, Stephen, 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Kam King Souvznlasy, 1975-1979 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Third Sector - General, 1978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Third Sector - Article (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Third Sector - Corporation Survey, JDR 3rd Fund, 1978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Third Sector, 1973-1979 (Box 2, Folder 33)
- Third Sector - Yale, 1976-1977 (Box 2, Folder 34)
- United Nations University, 1976-1977 (Box 2, Folder 35)
- U Thant, 1976-1977 (Box 2, Folder 36)
- Correspondene - W, 1974-1979 (Box 2, Folder 37)
- Joseph Wilson Awards, 1975-1979 (Box 2, Folder 38)
- Ed Young, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 39)
- Correspondence - Y-Z, 1975-1979 (Box 2, Folder 40)
- Chronological File, 1973-1977 (Box 2, Folder 41-48)